

2535 Whippletree Lane, Brookfield, WI 53045-4278 262.373.8175 perry@bertlenorg blog.hertlenorg github.com/perrygh

PROFILE

I am a Ruby on Rails and iOS Developer with **over** 15 years experience **delivering** highly performant well crafted software in a wide variety of software systems including embedded, real-time, distributed, desktop, and web applications using agile best practices. I have delivered over 30 applications on time, on budget, and feature complete.

I am particularly interested in fully utilizing my high productivity and wide breadth of skills at a small product-based company.

EXPERIENCE

Team Lead, Remote Independent Consultant for Fidelity LIfe Insurance (FLA)

2011-Present

FLA is transitioning to a product company.

Responsibilities

• Lead a large team on a major SOA effort for a new product involving 13 Padrino services, 4 Rails 3.2 applications, 10 custom gems, MongoDB, Postgres, RabbitMQ, and Backbone.js.

Team Lead, G5 Platform, Portland, OR

2011

G5 provides online marketing solutions to self-storage, student-housing, and senior living properties.

Responsibilities

- Lead two teams (mobile and reporting)
- Upgraded entire platform entire platform to Rails 3 while also significantly refactoring the platform to include unit tests and RESTful routes

CTO and Lead Rails Developer, Pathfinder Development, Chicago, IL

2009-2011

Pathfinder is a consulting firm that specializes in delivering MVP for startup companies.

Projects

• DataColor Colorspot (iOS 4) - Lead Developer

Colorspot is an iPhone application used by interior designers to capture color swatches and then visualize the swatch on surfaces, compare it to another swatch, view color harmony, lookup similar colors, and share the swatch.

• seasonalbids.com (Rails 3) - Lead Developer

SeasonalBids provides property managers (PMs) a place to author and public request for bids (RFBs). Contractors can then search for RFBs in their area and bid on them up until the deadline date, which is set by the property manager. PMs can then award contracts to the winning contractors.

• pod-cme.com (Rails 3) - Lead Developer

pod-cme is used by physicians to participate in clinical studies and obtain CME credits. Administrators of the site can build clinical area questionnaires and provide education material in documents, podcasts, or videos.

nailyourmortgage.com (Rails 2.3) - Senior Developer nailyourmortgage provides wholesale mortgages to home buyers and refinancers.

Technical Software Architect, Redpoint Technologies, Chicago, IL

2007-2009

Projects

• britetab.com (groovy)

BriteTab is a rich content online resume builder. Videos and images can be embedded in a traditional resume.

• global time and expense (ASP.Net)

The global time and expense application is used in over 50 countries by over 300,000 users.

Enterprise Architect, Consultant for Department of Energy, Albuquerque, NM

2001-2007

I designed and developed multiple systems used to identify and locate national security threats.

Software Engineer, INRI, San Diego, CA

1999-2001

I designed and developed multiple distributed communication systems used by the Department of Defense.

EDUCATION

University of Wisconsin - Madison B.S. with double major in Computer Science and Mathematics

SKILLS

Langauges

Ruby, Java, C#, Objective-C, C++

Frameworks/Databases

Ruby on Rails, JQuery, MySQL, Postgres, Oracle **Testing** Real TDD, Cucumber, RSpec

Platform/Tools

Heroku, EC2, S3, RDS, Cloudfront, Passenger, Git, OSX, Linux

Performance

Rapid application development, load testing, profiling, instrumentation, code optimization, database optimization

Communication

Conference speaker, blog contributor, productive telecommuter